<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Weakness xmlns="http://cwe.mitre.org/cwe-7" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" ID="1422" Name="Exposure of Sensitive Information caused by Incorrect Data Forwarding during Transient Execution" Abstraction="Base" Structure="Simple" Status="Incomplete">
		  <Description>A processor event or prediction may allow incorrect or stale data to
		  be forwarded to transient operations, potentially exposing data over a
		  covert channel.</Description>
		  <Extended_Description>
			<xhtml:p>Software may use a variety of techniques to preserve the
			confidentiality of private data that is accessible within the current
			processor context. For example, the memory safety and type safety
			properties of some high-level programming languages help to prevent
			software written in those languages from exposing private data. As a
			second example, software sandboxes may co-locate multiple users'
			software within a single process. The processor's Instruction Set
			Architecture (ISA) may permit one user's software to access another
			user's data (because the software shares the same address space), but
			the sandbox prevents these accesses by using software techniques such
			as bounds checking.</xhtml:p>
			
			<xhtml:p>If incorrect or stale data can be forwarded (for example, from a
			cache) to transient operations, then the operations'
			microarchitectural side effects may correspond to the data. If an
			attacker can trigger these transient operations and observe their side
			effects through a covert channel, then the attacker may be able to
			infer the data. For example, an attacker process may induce transient
			execution in a victim process that causes the victim to inadvertently
			access and then expose its private data via a covert channel. In the
			software sandbox example, an attacker sandbox may induce transient
			execution in its own code, allowing it to transiently access and
			expose data in a victim sandbox that shares the same address space.</xhtml:p>
			
			<xhtml:p>Consequently, weaknesses that arise from incorrect/stale data
			forwarding might violate users' expectations of software-based memory
			safety and isolation techniques. If the data forwarding behavior is
			not properly documented by the hardware vendor, this might violate the
			software vendor's expectation of how the hardware should behave.</xhtml:p>
		  </Extended_Description>
		  <Related_Weaknesses>
			<Related_Weakness Nature="ChildOf" CWE_ID="1420" View_ID="1000" Ordinal="Primary" />
			<Related_Weakness Nature="ChildOf" CWE_ID="1420" View_ID="1194" Ordinal="Primary" />
		  </Related_Weaknesses>
         <Weakness_Ordinalities>
            <Weakness_Ordinality>
               <Ordinality>Primary</Ordinality>
            </Weakness_Ordinality>
         </Weakness_Ordinalities>
			<Applicable_Platforms>
			  <Language Class="Not Language-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
			  <Operating_System Class="Not OS-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
			  <Architecture Class="Not Architecture-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
			  <Technology Class="Not Technology-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
			</Applicable_Platforms>
			<Modes_Of_Introduction>
			  <Introduction>
				<Phase>Architecture and Design</Phase>
				<Note><xhtml:p>This weakness can be introduced by data speculation techniques,
				or when the processor pipeline is designed to check exception
				conditions concurrently with other operations. This weakness can also
				persist after a CWE-1421 weakness has been mitigated. For example,
				suppose that a processor can forward stale data from a shared
				microarchitectural buffer to dependent transient operations, and
				furthermore suppose that the processor has been patched to flush the
				buffer on context switches. This mitigates the CWE-1421 weakness, but the
				stale-data forwarding behavior may persist as a CWE-1422 weakness unless
				this behavior is also patched.</xhtml:p>
				</Note>
			  </Introduction>
			</Modes_Of_Introduction>
			<Common_Consequences>
				<Consequence>
					<Scope>Confidentiality</Scope>
					<Impact>Read Memory</Impact>
					<Likelihood>Medium</Likelihood>
				</Consequence>
			</Common_Consequences>
			<Detection_Methods>
              <Detection_Method>
				<Method>Automated Static Analysis</Method>
				<Description><xhtml:p>A variety of automated static analysis tools can identify
				potentially exploitable code sequences in software. These tools may
				perform the analysis on source code, on binary code, or on an
				intermediate code representation (for example, during compilation).</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes>Automated static analysis may not reveal all weaknesses in a processor
				specification and should be combined with other detection methods to improve coverage.</Effectiveness_Notes>
              </Detection_Method>
              <Detection_Method>
				<Method>Manual Analysis</Method>
				<Description><xhtml:p>This weakness can be detected in hardware by manually
				inspecting processor specifications. Features that exhibit this
				weakness may include microarchitectural predictors, access control
				checks that occur out-of-order, or any other features that can allow
				operations to execute without committing to architectural state.Hardware designers can also scrutinize aspects
				of the instruction set architecture that have undefined
				behavior; these can become a focal point
				when applying other detection methods.
				</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes>Manual analysis may not reveal all weaknesses in a processor specification
				and should be combined with other detection methods to improve coverage.</Effectiveness_Notes>
              </Detection_Method>
              <Detection_Method>
				<Method>Automated Analysis</Method>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Software vendors can release tools that detect presence of known
				weaknesses on a processor. For example, some of these tools can
				attempt to transiently execute a vulnerable code sequence and detect
				whether code successfully leaks data in a manner consistent with the
				weakness under test. Alternatively, some hardware vendors provide
				enumeration for the presence of a weakness (or lack of a
				weakness). These enumeration bits can be checked and reported by
				system software. For example, Linux supports these checks for many
				commodity processors:</xhtml:p>
				<xhtml:p>$ cat /proc/cpuinfo | grep bugs | head -n 1</xhtml:p>
				<xhtml:p>bugs            : cpu_meltdown spectre_v1 spectre_v2 spec_store_bypass l1tf mds swapgs taa itlb_multihit srbds mmio_stale_data retbleed</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>High</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes>This method can be useful for detecting whether a processor if affected by known weaknesses, but it may not be useful for detecting unknown weaknesses.
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
              </Detection_Method>
			</Detection_Methods>
			<Potential_Mitigations>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Architecture and Design</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>The hardware designer can attempt to prevent transient
				execution from causing observable discrepancies in specific covert
				channels.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Limited</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes>Instructions or features that constrain transient execution or suppress its side effects may impact performance.</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Requirements</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Processor designers, system software vendors, or other
				agents may choose to restrict the ability of unprivileged software to
				access to high-resolution timers that are commonly used to monitor
				covert channels.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Defense in Depth</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes>Disabling specific predictors or other hardware features may result in significant performance overhead.</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Requirements</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Processor designers may expose instructions or other
				architectural features that allow software to mitigate the effects of
				transient execution, but without disabling predictors. These features
				may also help to limit opportunities for data exposure.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Instructions or features that constrain transient
				execution or suppress its side effects may impact performance.</xhtml:p>
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Requirements</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Processor designers may expose registers (for example,
				control registers or model-specific registers) that allow privileged
				and/or user software to disable specific predictors or other hardware
				features that can cause confidential data to be exposed during
				transient execution.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Limited</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Disabling specific predictors or other hardware
				features may result in significant performance overhead.</xhtml:p>
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Use software techniques (including the use of
				serialization instructions) that are intended to reduce the number of
				instructions that can be executed transiently after a processor event
				or misprediction.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Incidental</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Some transient execution weaknesses can be
				exploited even if a single instruction is executed transiently after a
				processor event or mis-prediction. This mitigation strategy has many
				other pitfalls that prevent it from eliminating this weakness
				entirely. For example, see [REF-1389].</xhtml:p>
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Isolate sandboxes or managed runtimes in separate address
				spaces (separate processes).</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>High</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Process isolation is also an effective strategy
				to mitigate many other kinds of weaknesses.</xhtml:p>
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Include serialization instructions (for example, LFENCE)
				that prevent processor events or mis-predictions prior to the
				serialization instruction from causing transient execution after the
				serialization instruction. For some weaknesses, a serialization
				instruction can also prevent a processor event or a mis-prediction
				from occurring after the serialization instruction (for example,
				CVE-2018-3639 can allow a processor to predict that a load will not
				depend on an older store; a serialization instruction between the
				store and the load may allow the store to update memory and prevent
				the mis-prediction from happening at all).</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>When used to comprehensively mitigate a transient
				execution weakness, serialization instructions can introduce
				significant performance overhead.</xhtml:p>
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>Use software techniques that can mitigate the
				consequences of transient execution. For example, address masking can
				be used in some circumstances to prevent out-of-bounds transient
				reads.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Limited</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Address masking and related software mitigation
				techniques have been used to harden specific code sequences that could
				potentially be exploited via transient execution. For example, the
				Linux kernel makes limited use of this technique to mitigate
				bounds-check bypass [REF-1390].</xhtml:p>
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>If the weakness is exposed by a single instruction (or a
				small set of instructions), then the compiler (or JIT, etc.) can be
				configured to prevent the affected instruction(s) from being
				generated, and instead generate an alternate sequence of instructions
				that is not affected by the weakness.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>Limited</Effectiveness>
				<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>This technique is only effective for software
				that is compiled with this mitigation.</xhtml:p>
				</Effectiveness_Notes>
			  </Mitigation>
			  <Mitigation>
				<Phase>Documentation</Phase>
				<Description><xhtml:p>If a hardware feature can allow incorrect or stale data
				to be forwarded to transient operations, the hardware designer may opt
				to disclose this behavior in architecture documentation. This
				documentation can inform users about potential consequences and
				effective mitigations.</xhtml:p>
				</Description>
				<Effectiveness>High</Effectiveness>
			  </Mitigation>
			</Potential_Mitigations>
			<Demonstrative_Examples>
			  <Demonstrative_Example>
				<Intro_Text><xhtml:p>Faulting loads in a victim domain may trigger incorrect transient
				forwarding, which leaves secret-dependent traces in the
				microarchitectural state. Consider this code sequence example from
				[REF-1391].</xhtml:p>
				</Intro_Text>
				<Example_Code Nature="Bad" Language="C">
				  <xhtml:br />
				  void call_victim(size_t untrusted_arg) {<xhtml:br />
				  <xhtml:div style="margin-left:1em;">
					*arg_copy = untrusted_arg;<xhtml:br />
					array[**trusted_ptr * 4096];<xhtml:br />
				  </xhtml:div>
				  }<xhtml:br />
				</Example_Code>
				<Body_Text><xhtml:p>A processor with this weakness will store the value of untrusted_arg
				(which may be provided by an attacker) to the stack, which is trusted
				memory. Additionally, this store operation will save this value in
				some microarchitectural buffer, for example, the store buffer.</xhtml:p>

				<xhtml:p>In this code sequence, trusted_ptr is dereferenced while the attacker
				forces a page fault. The faulting load causes the processor to
				mis-speculate by forwarding untrusted_arg as the (transient) load
				result. The processor then uses untrusted_arg for the pointer
				dereference. After the fault has been handled and the load has been
				re-issued with the correct argument, secret-dependent information
				stored at the address of trusted_ptr remains in microarchitectural
				state and can be extracted by an attacker using a vulnerable code
				sequence.</xhtml:p>
				</Body_Text>
			  </Demonstrative_Example>
			  <Demonstrative_Example>
				<Intro_Text><xhtml:p>Some processors try to predict when a store will forward data to a
				subsequent load, even when the address of the store or the load is not
				yet known. For example, on Intel processors this feature is called a
				Fast Store Forwarding Predictor [REF-1392], and on AMD processors the
				feature is called Predictive Store Forwarding [REF-1393]. A
				misprediction can cause incorrect or stale data to be forwarded from a
				store to a load, as illustrated in the following code snippet from
				[REF-1393]:</xhtml:p>
				</Intro_Text>
				<Example_Code Nature="Bad" Language="C">
				  <xhtml:br />
				  void fn(int idx) {<xhtml:br />
				  <xhtml:div style="margin-left:1em;">
					unsigned char v;<xhtml:br />
					idx_array[0] = 4096;<xhtml:br />
					v = array[idx_array[idx] * (idx)];<xhtml:br />
				  </xhtml:div>
				  }<xhtml:br />
				</Example_Code>
				<Body_Text><xhtml:p>In this example, assume that the parameter idx can only be 0 or 1, and
				assume that idx_array initially contains all 0s. Observe that the
				assignment to v in line 4 will be array[0], regardless of whether
				idx=0 or idx=1. Now suppose that an attacker repeatedly invokes fn
				with idx=0 to train the store forwarding predictor to predict that the
				store in line 3 will forward the data 4096 to the load idx_array[idx]
				in line 4. Then, when the attacker invokes fn with idx=1 the predictor
				may cause idx_array[idx] to transiently produce the incorrect value
				4096, and therefore v will transiently be assigned the value
				array[4096], which otherwise would not have been accessible in line 4.</xhtml:p>

				<xhtml:p>Although this toy example is benign (it doesn't transmit array[4096]
				over a covert channel), an attacker may be able to use similar
				techniques to craft and train malicious code sequences to, for
				example, read data beyond a software sandbox boundary.</xhtml:p>
				</Body_Text>
			  </Demonstrative_Example>
			</Demonstrative_Examples>
			<Observed_Examples>
			  <Observed_Example>
				<Reference>CVE-2020-0551</Reference>
				<Description>A fault, microcode assist, or abort may allow transient
				load operations to forward malicious stale data to dependent
				operations executed by a victim, causing the victim to unintentionally
				access and potentially expose its own data over a covert channel.
				</Description>
				<Link>https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2020-0551</Link>
			  </Observed_Example>
			  <Observed_Example>
				<Reference>CVE-2020-8698</Reference>
				<Description>A fast store forwarding predictor may allow store
				operations to forward incorrect data to transient load operations,
				potentially exposing data over a covert channel.
				</Description>
				<Link>https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2020-8698</Link>
			  </Observed_Example>
			</Observed_Examples>
			<References>
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1389" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1390" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1391" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1392" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1393" />
			</References>
			<Mapping_Notes>
              <Usage>Allowed</Usage>
              <Rationale>This CWE entry is at the Base level of abstraction, which is a preferred level of abstraction for mapping to the root causes of vulnerabilities
			  </Rationale>
              <Comments>Use only when the weakness arises from forwarding of
			  incorrect/stale data, and the data is not architecturally
			  restricted (that is, the forwarded data is accessible within the current processor context).
			  <xhtml:p>If a weakness arises from forwarding of
			  incorrect/stale data that is not accessible within the current
			  processor context, then CWE-1421 may be more appropriate for
			  the mapping task.</xhtml:p>
			  </Comments>
              <Reasons>
				<Reason Type="Acceptable-Use" />
              </Reasons>
			</Mapping_Notes>
			<Content_History>
				<Submission>
					<Submission_Name>Scott D. Constable</Submission_Name>
					<Submission_Organization>Intel Corporation</Submission_Organization>
					<Submission_Date>2023-09-19</Submission_Date>
					<Submission_Version>4.14</Submission_Version>
					<Submission_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Submission_ReleaseDate>
				</Submission>
				<Modification>
					<Modification_Name>CWE Content Team</Modification_Name>
					<Modification_Organization>MITRE</Modification_Organization>
					<Modification_Date>2025-12-11</Modification_Date>
					<Modification_Version>4.19</Modification_Version>
					<Modification_ReleaseDate>2025-12-11</Modification_ReleaseDate>
					<Modification_Comment>updated Weakness_Ordinalities</Modification_Comment>
				</Modification>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>David Kaplan</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>AMD</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Rafael Dossantos, Abraham Fernandez Rubio, Alric Althoff, Lyndon Fawcett</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Arm</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Members of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Jason Oberg</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Cycuity</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Priya B. Iyer</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Intel Corporation</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Nicole Fern</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Riscure</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
			</Content_History>
		</Weakness>
      