<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Weakness xmlns="http://cwe.mitre.org/cwe-7" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" ID="1434" Name="Insecure Setting of Generative AI/ML Model Inference Parameters" Abstraction="Base" Structure="Simple" Status="Draft">
	  <Description>The product has a component that relies on a
	  generative AI/ML model configured with inference parameters that
	  produce an unacceptably high rate of erroneous or unexpected
	  outputs.</Description>
	  <Extended_Description>
		<xhtml:p>Generative AI/ML models, such as those used for text
		generation, image synthesis, and other creative tasks, rely on
		inference parameters that control model behavior, such as
		temperature, Top P, and Top K.  These parameters affect the
		model's internal decision-making processes, learning rate, and
		probability distributions. Incorrect settings can lead to
		unusual behavior such as text "hallucinations," unrealistic
		images, or failure to converge during training. The impact of
		such misconfigurations can compromise the integrity of the
		application. If the results are used in security-critical
		operations or decisions, then this could violate the intended
		security policy, i.e., introduce a vulnerability.</xhtml:p>
	  </Extended_Description>
	  <Related_Weaknesses>
		<Related_Weakness Nature="ChildOf" CWE_ID="440" View_ID="1000" Ordinal="Primary" />
		<Related_Weakness Nature="ChildOf" CWE_ID="665" View_ID="1000" />
		<Related_Weakness Nature="CanPrecede" CWE_ID="684" View_ID="1000" />
		<Related_Weakness Nature="PeerOf" CWE_ID="691" View_ID="1000" />
	  </Related_Weaknesses>
	  <Weakness_Ordinalities>
        <Weakness_Ordinality>
          <Ordinality>Primary</Ordinality>
        </Weakness_Ordinality>
	  </Weakness_Ordinalities>
		<Applicable_Platforms>
		  <Language Class="Not Language-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
		  <Architecture Class="Not Architecture-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
		  <Technology Name="AI/ML" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
		  <Technology Class="Not Technology-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
		</Applicable_Platforms>
		<Modes_Of_Introduction>
		  <Introduction>
			<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
			<Note>During model training, hyperparameters may be set
			without adequate validation or understanding of their
			impact.</Note>
		  </Introduction>
		  <Introduction>
			<Phase>Installation</Phase>
			<Note>During deployment, model parameters may be adjusted
			to optimize performance without comprehensive
			testing.</Note>
		  </Introduction>
		  <Introduction>
			<Phase>Patching and Maintenance</Phase>
			<Note>Updates or modifications may be made to the model
			that alter its behavior without thorough
			re-evaluation.</Note>
		  </Introduction>
		</Modes_Of_Introduction>
		<Common_Consequences>
		  <Consequence>
			<Scope>Integrity</Scope>
			<Scope>Other</Scope>
			<Impact>Varies by Context</Impact>
			<Impact>Unexpected State</Impact>
			<Note>The product can generate inaccurate, misleading, or
			nonsensical information.</Note>
		  </Consequence>
		  <Consequence>
			<Scope>Other</Scope>
			<Impact>Alter Execution Logic</Impact>
			<Impact>Unexpected State</Impact>
			<Impact>Varies by Context</Impact>
			<Note>If outputs are used in critical decision-making
			processes, errors could be propagated to other systems or
			components.</Note>
		  </Consequence>
		</Common_Consequences>
        <Detection_Methods>
          <Detection_Method>
            <Method>Automated Dynamic Analysis</Method>
            <Description>Manipulate inference parameters and perform
            comparative evaluation to assess the impact of selected
            values. Build a suite of systems using targeted tools that
            detect problems such as prompt injection (CWE-1427) and
            other problems.  Consider statistically measuring token
            distribution to see if it is consistent with expected
            results.</Description>
            <Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
            <Effectiveness_Notes>Given the large variety of outcomes,
            it can be difficult to design testing to be comprehensive
            enough, and there is still a risk of unpredictable
            behavior.</Effectiveness_Notes>
          </Detection_Method>
          <Detection_Method>
            <Method>Manual Dynamic Analysis</Method>
            <Description>Manipulate inference parameters and perform
            comparative evaluation to assess the impact of selected
            values. Build a suite of systems using targeted tools that
            detect problems such as prompt injection (CWE-1427) and
            other problems.  Consider statistically measuring token
            distribution to see if it is consistent with expected
            results.</Description>
            <Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
            <Effectiveness_Notes>Given the large variety of outcomes,
            it can be difficult to design testing to be comprehensive
            enough, and there is still a risk of unpredictable
            behavior.</Effectiveness_Notes>
          </Detection_Method>
        </Detection_Methods>
		<Potential_Mitigations>
		  <Mitigation>
			<Phase>Implementation</Phase>
			<Phase>System Configuration</Phase>
			<Phase>Operation</Phase>
			<Description>Develop and adhere to robust parameter tuning
			processes that include extensive testing and
			validation.</Description>
		  </Mitigation>
		  <Mitigation>
			<Phase>Implementation</Phase>
			<Phase>System Configuration</Phase>
			<Phase>Operation</Phase>
			<Description>Implement feedback mechanisms to continuously
			assess and adjust model performance.</Description>
		  </Mitigation>
		  <Mitigation>
			<Phase>Documentation</Phase>
			<Description>Provide comprehensive documentation and
			guidelines for parameter settings to ensure consistent and
			accurate model behavior.</Description>
		  </Mitigation>
		</Potential_Mitigations>
		<Demonstrative_Examples>
		  <Demonstrative_Example>
			<Intro_Text><xhtml:p>Assume the product offers an
			LLM-based AI coding assistant to help users to write code
			as part of an Integrated Development Environment (IDE).
			Assume the model has been trained on real-world code, and
			the model behaves normally under its default settings.
			Suppose there is a default temperature of 1, with a range
			of temperature values from 0 (most deterministic) to
			2.</xhtml:p>
			<xhtml:p>Consider the following configuration.</xhtml:p>
			</Intro_Text>
			<Example_Code Nature="Bad" Language="JSON">
			  {<xhtml:br />
			  <xhtml:div style="margin-left:1em;">
				"model": "my-coding-model",<xhtml:br />
				"context_window": 8192,<xhtml:br />
				"max_output_tokens": 4096,<xhtml:br />
				"temperature", 1.5,<xhtml:br />
				...<xhtml:br />
			  </xhtml:div>
			  }
			</Example_Code>
			<Body_Text><xhtml:p>The problem is that the configuration contains a temperature
			hyperparameter that is higher than the default. This significantly
			increases the likelihood that the LLM will suggest a package that did
			not exist at training time, a behavior sometimes referred to as
			"package hallucination."  Note that other possible behaviors could
			arise from higher temperature, not just package hallucination.</xhtml:p>
			<xhtml:p>An adversary could anticipate which package names could be generated
			and create a malicious package. For example, it has been observed that
			the same LLM might hallucinate the same package regularly. Any code
			that is generated by the LLM, when run by the user, would download and
			execute the malicious package. This is similar to typosquatting.</xhtml:p>
			<xhtml:p>The risk could be reduced by lowering the temperature so that it
			reduces the unpredictable outputs and has a better chance of staying
			more in line with the training data. If the temperature is set too
			low, then some of the power of the model will be lost, and it may be
			less capable of producing solutions for rarely-encountered problems
			that are not reflected in the training data. However, if the
			temperature is not set low enough, the risk of hallucinating package
			names may still be too high.  Unfortunately, the "best" temperature
			cannot be determined a priori, and sufficient empirical testing is
			needed.</xhtml:p>
			</Body_Text>
			<Example_Code Nature="Good" Language="JSON">
			  {<xhtml:br />
			  <xhtml:div style="margin-left:1em;">
				...<xhtml:br />
				"temperature", 0.2,<xhtml:br />
				...<xhtml:br />
			  </xhtml:div>
			  }<xhtml:br />
			</Example_Code>
			<Body_Text>
			  <xhtml:p>In addition to more restrictive temperature settings, consider adding
			  guardrails that test that independently verify any referenced package
			  to ensure that it exists, is not obsolete, and comes from a trusted
			  party.</xhtml:p>
			  <xhtml:p>Note that reducing temperature does not entirely eliminate the risk of
			  package hallucination.  Even with very low temperatures or other
			  settings, there is still a small chance that a non-existent package
			  name will be generated.</xhtml:p>
			</Body_Text>
		  </Demonstrative_Example>
		</Demonstrative_Examples>
		<References>
		  <Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1487" />
		</References>
        <Mapping_Notes>
          <Usage>Allowed</Usage>
          <Rationale>This CWE entry is at the Base level of abstraction, which is a preferred level of abstraction for mapping to the root causes of vulnerabilities.</Rationale>
          <Comments>Carefully read both the name and description to ensure that this mapping is an appropriate fit. Do not try to 'force' a mapping to a lower-level Base/Variant simply to comply with this preferred level of abstraction.</Comments>
          <Reasons>
            <Reason Type="Acceptable-Use" />
          </Reasons>
        </Mapping_Notes>
		<Notes>
		  <Note Type="Research Gap">
			This weakness might be under-reported as of CWE 4.18,
			since there are no clear observed examples in
			CVE. However, inference parameters may be the root cause
			for various vulnerabilities - or important factors - but
			the vulnerability reports may concentrate more on the
			negative impact (e.g. code execution) or the weaknesses
			that the insecure settings contribute to. Alternately,
			dynamic techniques might not reveal the root cause if the
			researcher does not have access to the underlying source
			code and environment.</Note>
		</Notes>
		<Content_History>
		  <Submission>
			<Submission_Name>Lily Wong</Submission_Name>
			<Submission_Organization>MITRE</Submission_Organization>
			<Submission_Date>2024-06-28</Submission_Date>
			<Submission_Version>4.18</Submission_Version>
			<Submission_ReleaseDate>2025-09-09</Submission_ReleaseDate>
		  </Submission>
				<Modification>
					<Modification_Name>CWE Content Team</Modification_Name>
					<Modification_Organization>MITRE</Modification_Organization>
					<Modification_Date>2026-04-30</Modification_Date>
					<Modification_Version>4.20</Modification_Version>
					<Modification_ReleaseDate>2026-04-30</Modification_ReleaseDate>
					<Modification_Comment>updated Relationships</Modification_Comment>
				</Modification>
          <Contribution Type="Content">
            <Contribution_Name>AI WG "New Entry" subgroup</Contribution_Name>
            <Contribution_Date>2025-02-28</Contribution_Date>
			<Contribution_Version>4.18</Contribution_Version>
			<Contribution_ReleaseDate>2025-09-09</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
            <Contribution_Comment>Participated in regular meetings from February to August 2025 to develop and refine most elements of this entry.</Contribution_Comment>
          </Contribution>
		</Content_History>
	  </Weakness>
      