<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Weakness xmlns="http://cwe.mitre.org/cwe-7" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" ID="1423" Name="Exposure of Sensitive Information caused by Shared Microarchitectural Predictor State that Influences Transient Execution" Abstraction="Base" Structure="Simple" Status="Incomplete">
			<Description>Shared microarchitectural predictor state may allow code to influence
				transient execution across a hardware boundary, potentially exposing
				data that is accessible beyond the boundary over a covert channel.
			</Description>
			<Extended_Description>
				<xhtml:p>Many commodity processors have Instruction Set Architecture (ISA)
				features that protect software components from one another. These
				features can include memory segmentation, virtual memory, privilege
				rings, trusted execution environments, and virtual machines, among
				others. For example, virtual memory provides each process with its own
				address space, which prevents processes from accessing each other's
				private data. Many of these features can be used to form
				hardware-enforced security boundaries between software components.</xhtml:p>
				<xhtml:p>When separate software components (for example, two processes) share
				microarchitectural predictor state across a hardware boundary, code in
				one component may be able to influence microarchitectural predictor
				behavior in another component. If the predictor can cause transient
				execution, the shared predictor state may allow an attacker to
				influence transient execution in a victim, and in a manner that could
				allow the attacker to infer private data from the victim by monitoring
				observable discrepancies (CWE-203) in a covert channel [REF-1400].</xhtml:p>
				<xhtml:p>Predictor state may be shared when the processor transitions from one
				component to another (for example, when a process makes a system call
				to enter the kernel). Many commodity processors have features which
				prevent microarchitectural predictions that occur before a boundary
				from influencing predictions that occur after the boundary.</xhtml:p>
				<xhtml:p>Predictor state may also be shared between hardware threads, for
				example, sibling hardware threads on a processor that supports
				simultaneous multithreading (SMT). This sharing may be benign if the
				hardware threads are simultaneously executing in the same software
				component, or it could expose a weakness if one sibling is a malicious
				software component, and the other sibling is a victim software
				component. Processors that share microarchitectural predictors between
				hardware threads may have features which prevent microarchitectural
				predictions that occur on one hardware thread from influencing
				predictions that occur on another hardware thread.</xhtml:p>
				<xhtml:p>Features that restrict predictor state sharing across transitions or
				between hardware threads may be always-on, on by default, or may
				require opt-in from software.</xhtml:p>
			</Extended_Description>
			<Related_Weaknesses>
				<Related_Weakness Nature="ChildOf" CWE_ID="1420" View_ID="1000" Ordinal="Primary" />
				<Related_Weakness Nature="ChildOf" CWE_ID="1420" View_ID="1194" Ordinal="Primary" />
			</Related_Weaknesses>
         <Weakness_Ordinalities>
            <Weakness_Ordinality>
               <Ordinality>Primary</Ordinality>
            </Weakness_Ordinality>
         </Weakness_Ordinalities>
			<Applicable_Platforms>	
				<Language Class="Not Language-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
				<Operating_System Class="Not OS-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
				<Architecture Class="Not Architecture-Specific" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
				<Technology Name="Microcontroller Hardware" Prevalence="Undetermined" /><Technology Name="Processor Hardware" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
				<Technology Name="Memory Hardware" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
				<Technology Class="System on Chip" Prevalence="Undetermined" />
			</Applicable_Platforms>
			<Modes_Of_Introduction>
				<Introduction>
					<Phase>Architecture and Design</Phase>
					<Note><xhtml:p>This weakness can be introduced during hardware architecture and
					design if predictor state is not properly isolated between modes (for
					example, user mode and kernel mode), if predictor state is not
					isolated between hardware threads, or if it is not isolated between
					other kinds of execution contexts supported by the processor.</xhtml:p></Note>
				</Introduction>
				<Introduction>
					<Phase>Implementation</Phase>
					<Note><xhtml:p>This weakness can be introduced during system software
					implementation if predictor-state-sanitizing operations (for example,
					the indirect branch prediction barrier on Intel x86) are not invoked
					when switching from one context to another.</xhtml:p></Note>
				</Introduction>
				<Introduction>
					<Phase>System Configuration</Phase>
					<Note><xhtml:p>This weakness can be introduced if the system has not been
					configured according to the hardware vendor's recommendations for
					mitigating the weakness.</xhtml:p></Note>
				</Introduction>
			</Modes_Of_Introduction>
			<Common_Consequences>
				<Consequence>
					<Scope>Confidentiality</Scope>
					<Impact>Read Memory</Impact>
					<Likelihood>Medium</Likelihood>
				</Consequence>
			</Common_Consequences>
			<Detection_Methods>
				<Detection_Method>
					<Method>Manual Analysis</Method>
					<Description><xhtml:p>This weakness can be detected in hardware by manually
					inspecting processor specifications. Features that exhibit this
					weakness may have microarchitectural predictor state that is shared
					between hardware threads, execution contexts (for example, user and
					kernel), or other components that may host mutually distrusting
					software (or firmware, etc.).</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes>Manual analysis may not reveal all weaknesses in a processor specification and should be combined with other detection methods to improve coverage.</Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Detection_Method>
				<Detection_Method>
					<Method>Automated Analysis</Method>
					<Description><xhtml:p>Software vendors can release tools that detect presence of
					known weaknesses on a processor. For example, some of these tools can
					attempt to transiently execute a vulnerable code sequence and detect
					whether code successfully leaks data in a manner consistent with the
					weakness under test. Alternatively, some hardware vendors provide
					enumeration for the presence of a weakness (or lack of a
					weakness). These enumeration bits can be checked and reported by
					system software. For example, Linux supports these checks for many
					commodity processors:</xhtml:p>
					<xhtml:p>$ cat /proc/cpuinfo | grep bugs | head -n 1</xhtml:p>
					<xhtml:p>bugs            : cpu_meltdown spectre_v1 spectre_v2 spec_store_bypass l1tf mds swapgs taa itlb_multihit srbds mmio_stale_data retbleed</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>High</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes>This method can be useful for detecting whether a processor if affected by known weaknesses, but it may not be useful for detecting unknown weaknesses</Effectiveness_Notes>
            	</Detection_Method>
				<Detection_Method>
					<Method>Automated Analysis</Method>
					<Description><xhtml:p>This weakness can be detected in hardware by employing static
					or dynamic taint analysis methods [REF-1401]. These methods can label
					each predictor entry (or prediction history, etc.) according to the
					processor context that created it. Taint analysis or information flow
					analysis can then be applied to detect when predictor state created in
					one context can influence predictions made in another context.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes>Automated static or dynamic taint analysis may not reveal all weaknesses in a processor specification and should be combined with other detection methods to improve coverage.</Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Detection_Method>
			</Detection_Methods>
			<Potential_Mitigations>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Architecture and Design</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>The hardware designer can attempt to prevent transient
					execution from causing observable discrepancies in specific covert
					channels.</xhtml:p></Description>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Architecture and Design</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>Hardware designers may choose to use microarchitectural
					bits to tag predictor entries. For example, each predictor entry may
					be tagged with a kernel-mode bit which, when set, indicates that the
					predictor entry was created in kernel mode. The processor can use this
					bit to enforce that predictions in the current mode must have been
					trained in the current mode. This can prevent malicious cross-mode
					training, such as when user-mode software attempts to create predictor
					entries that influence transient execution in the kernel. Predictor
					entry tags can also be used to associate each predictor entry with the
					SMT thread that created it, and thus the processor can enforce that
					each predictor entry can only be used by the SMT thread that created
					it. This can prevent an SMT thread from using predictor entries
					crafted by a malicious sibling SMT thread.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Tagging can be highly effective for predictor
					state that is comprised of discrete elements, such as an array of
					recently visited branch targets. Predictor state can also have
					different representations that are not conducive to tagging. For
					example, some processors keep a compressed digest of branch history
					which does not contain discrete elements that can be individually
					tagged.</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Architecture and Design</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>Hardware designers may choose to sanitize
					microarchitectural predictor state (for example, branch prediction
					history) when the processor transitions to a different context, for
					example, whenever a system call is invoked. Alternatively, the
					hardware may expose instruction(s) that allow software to sanitize
					predictor state according to the user's threat model. For example,
					this can allow operating system software to sanitize predictor state
					when performing a context switch from one process to another.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>This technique may not be able to mitigate
					weaknesses that arise from predictor state that is shared across SMT
					threads. Sanitizing predictor state on context switches may also
					negatively impact performance, either by removing predictor entries
					that could be reused when returning to the previous context, or by
					slowing down the context switch itself.</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Implementation</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>System software can mitigate this weakness by invoking
					predictor-state-sanitizing operations (for example, the indirect
					branch prediction barrier on Intel x86) when switching from one
					context to another, according to the hardware vendor's
					recommendations.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>This technique may not be able to mitigate
					weaknesses that arise from predictor state shared across SMT
					threads. Sanitizing predictor state may also negatively impact
					performance in some circumstances.</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>If the weakness is exposed by a single instruction (or a
					small set of instructions), then the compiler (or JIT, etc.) can be
					configured to prevent the affected instruction(s) from being
					generated. One prominent example of this mitigation is retpoline
					([REF-1414]).</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Limited</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>This technique is only effective for software
					that is compiled with this mitigation. Additionally, an alternate
					instruction sequence may mitigate the weakness on some processors but
					not others, even when the processors share the same ISA. For example,
					retpoline has been documented as effective on some x86 processors, but
					not fully effective on other x86 processors.</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>Use control-flow integrity (CFI) techniques to constrain
					the behavior of instructions that redirect the instruction pointer,
					such as indirect branch instructions.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Some CFI techniques may not be able to constrain
					transient execution, even though they are effective at constraining
					architectural execution. Or they may be able to provide some
					additional protection against a transient execution weakness, but
					without comprehensively mitigating the weakness. For example,
					Clang-CFI provides strong architectural CFI properties and can make
					some transient execution weaknesses more difficult to exploit [REF-1398].</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Build and Compilation</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>Use software techniques (including the use of
					serialization instructions) that are intended to reduce the number of
					instructions that can be executed transiently after a processor event
					or misprediction.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Incidental</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Some transient execution weaknesses can be
					exploited even if a single instruction is executed transiently after a
					processor event or mis-prediction. This mitigation strategy has many
					other pitfalls that prevent it from eliminating this weakness
					entirely. For example, see [REF-1389].</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>System Configuration</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>Some systems may allow the user to disable predictor
					sharing. For example, this could be a BIOS configuration, or a
					model-specific register (MSR) that can be configured by the operating
					system or virtual machine monitor.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>Disabling predictor sharing can negatively impact
					performance for some workloads that benefit from shared predictor
					state.</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Patching and Maintenance</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>The hardware vendor may provide a patch to, for example,
					sanitize predictor state when the processor transitions to a different
					context, or to prevent predictor entries from being shared across SMT
					threads. A patch may also introduce new ISA that allows software to
					toggle a mitigation.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>Moderate</Effectiveness>
					<Effectiveness_Notes><xhtml:p>This mitigation may only be fully effective if
					the patch prevents predictor sharing across all contexts that are
					affected by the weakness. Additionally, sanitizing predictor state
					and/or preventing shared predictor state can negatively impact
					performance in some circumstances.</xhtml:p></Effectiveness_Notes>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Documentation</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>If a hardware feature can allow microarchitectural
					predictor state to be shared between contexts, SMT threads, or other
					architecturally defined boundaries, the hardware designer may opt to
					disclose this behavior in architecture documentation. This
					documentation can inform users about potential consequences and
					effective mitigations.</xhtml:p></Description>
					<Effectiveness>High</Effectiveness>
				</Mitigation>
				<Mitigation>
					<Phase>Requirements</Phase>
					<Description><xhtml:p>Processor designers, system software vendors, or other
					agents may choose to restrict the ability of unprivileged software to
					access to high-resolution timers that are commonly used to monitor
					covert channels.</xhtml:p></Description>
				</Mitigation>
			</Potential_Mitigations>
			<Demonstrative_Examples>
				<Demonstrative_Example>
					<Intro_Text><xhtml:p>Branch Target Injection (BTI) is a vulnerability that can allow an SMT
					hardware thread to maliciously train the indirect branch predictor
					state that is shared with its sibling hardware thread. A cross-thread
					BTI attack requires the attacker to find a vulnerable code sequence
					within the victim software. For example, the authors of [REF-1415]
					identified the following code sequence in the Windows library
					ntdll.dll:</xhtml:p></Intro_Text>
					<Example_Code Nature="Bad" Language="x86 Assembly">
					<xhtml:br />
						<xhtml:div style="margin-left:1em;">
						adc edi,dword ptr [ebx+edx+13BE13BDh]<xhtml:br />
						adc dl,byte ptr [edi]<xhtml:br />
						...<xhtml:br />
						</xhtml:div>
					indirect_branch_site:<xhtml:br />
						<xhtml:div style="margin-left:1em;">
						jmp dword ptr [rsi]   # at this point attacker knows edx, controls edi and ebx<xhtml:br />
						</xhtml:div>
					</Example_Code>
					<Body_Text>
					<xhtml:p>To successfully exploit this code sequence to disclose the victim's
					private data, the attacker must also be able to find an indirect
					branch site within the victim, where the attacker controls the values
					in edi and ebx, and the attacker knows the value in edx as shown above
					at the indirect branch site.</xhtml:p>
					<xhtml:p>A proof-of-concept cross-thread BTI attack might proceed as follows:</xhtml:p>
					<xhtml:ol>
						<xhtml:li>The attacker thread and victim thread must be co-scheduled on the same physical processor core.
						</xhtml:li>
						<xhtml:li>The attacker thread must train the shared branch predictor so that
					when the victim thread reaches indirect_branch_site, the jmp
					instruction will be predicted to target example_code_sequence instead
					of the correct architectural target. The training procedure may vary
					by processor, and the attacker may need to reverse-engineer the branch
					predictor to identify a suitable training algorithm.
						</xhtml:li>
						<xhtml:li>This step assumes that the attacker can control some values in the
					victim program, specifically the values in edi and ebx at
					indirect_branch_site. When the victim reaches indirect_branch_site the
					processor will (mis)predict example_code_sequence as the target and
					(transiently) execute the adc instructions. If the attacker chooses
					ebx so that `ebx = m
						<xhtml:ul>
						  <xhtml:li>
							0x13BE13BD - edx, then the first adc will load 32 bits from
							address m in the victim's address space and add *m (the data loaded from)
							to the attacker-controlled base address in edi. The second
							adc instruction accesses a location in memory whose address corresponds
							to *m`.
						  </xhtml:li>
						</xhtml:ul>
						</xhtml:li>
						<xhtml:li>The adversary uses a covert channel analysis technique such as
					Flush+Reload ([REF-1416]) to infer the value of the victim's private data
					*m.
						</xhtml:li>
					</xhtml:ol>
					</Body_Text>
				</Demonstrative_Example>
				<Demonstrative_Example>
					<Intro_Text><xhtml:p>BTI can also allow software in one execution context to maliciously
					train branch predictor entries that can be used in another
					context. For example, on some processors user-mode software may be
					able to train predictor entries that can also be used after
					transitioning into kernel mode, such as after invoking a system
					call. This vulnerability does not necessarily require SMT and may
					instead be performed in synchronous steps, though it does require the
					attacker to find an exploitable code sequence in the victim's code,
					for example, in the kernel.</xhtml:p></Intro_Text>
				</Demonstrative_Example>
			</Demonstrative_Examples>
			<Observed_Examples>
				<Observed_Example>
					<Reference>CVE-2017-5754</Reference>
					<Description>(Branch Target Injection, BTI, Spectre v2). Shared
					microarchitectural indirect branch predictor state may allow code to
					influence transient execution across a process, VM, or privilege
					boundary, potentially exposing data that is accessible beyond the
					boundary.</Description>
					<Link>https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2017-5754</Link>
				</Observed_Example>
				<Observed_Example>
					<Reference>CVE-2022-0001</Reference>
					<Description>(Branch History Injection, BHI, Spectre-BHB). Shared
					branch history state may allow user-mode code to influence transient
					execution in the kernel, potentially exposing kernel data over a
					covert channel.</Description>
					<Link>https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2022-0001</Link>
				</Observed_Example>
				<Observed_Example>
					<Reference>CVE-2021-33149</Reference>
					<Description>(RSB underflow, Retbleed). Shared return stack buffer
					state may allow code that executes before a prediction barrier to
					influence transient execution after the prediction barrier,
					potentially exposing data that is accessible beyond the barrier over a
					covert channel.</Description>
					<Link>https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2021-33149</Link>
				</Observed_Example>
			</Observed_Examples>
			<References>
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1414" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1415" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1416" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1398" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1389" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1400" />
				<Reference External_Reference_ID="REF-1401" />
			</References>
         <Mapping_Notes>
            <Usage>Allowed</Usage>
            <Rationale>This CWE entry is at the Base level of abstraction, which is a preferred level of abstraction for mapping to the root causes of vulnerabilities
			</Rationale>
			<Comments>Use only when the weakness allows code in one processor context to influence the predictions of code in another processor context via predictor state that is shared between the two contexts. For example, Branch Target Injection, an instance of CWE-1423, can be mitigated by tagging each indirect branch predictor entry according to the processor context in which the entry was created, thus preventing entries created in one context from being used in a different context. However, the mitigated indirect branch predictor can still expose different weaknesses where malicious predictor entries created in one context are used later in the same context (context tags cannot prevent this). One such example is Intra-mode Branch Target Injection. Weaknesses of this sort can map to CWE-1420.</Comments>
            <Reasons>
               <Reason Type="Acceptable-Use" />
            </Reasons>
			<Suggestions>
				<Suggestion CWE_ID="1420" Comment="If a weakness involves a microarchitectural predictor whose state is not shared across processor contexts, then CWE-1420 may be more appropriate for the mapping task." />
			</Suggestions>
         </Mapping_Notes>
			<Content_History>
				<Submission>
					<Submission_Name>Scott D. Constable</Submission_Name>
					<Submission_Organization>Intel Corporation</Submission_Organization>
					<Submission_Date>2023-09-19</Submission_Date>
					<Submission_Version>4.14</Submission_Version>
					<Submission_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Submission_ReleaseDate>
				</Submission>
				<Modification>
					<Modification_Name>CWE Content Team</Modification_Name>
					<Modification_Organization>MITRE</Modification_Organization>
					<Modification_Date>2025-09-09</Modification_Date>
					<Modification_Version>4.18</Modification_Version>
					<Modification_ReleaseDate>2025-09-09</Modification_ReleaseDate>
					<Modification_Comment>updated Relationships</Modification_Comment>
				</Modification>
				<Modification>
					<Modification_Name>CWE Content Team</Modification_Name>
					<Modification_Organization>MITRE</Modification_Organization>
					<Modification_Date>2025-12-11</Modification_Date>
					<Modification_Version>4.19</Modification_Version>
					<Modification_ReleaseDate>2025-12-11</Modification_ReleaseDate>
					<Modification_Comment>updated Weakness_Ordinalities</Modification_Comment>
				</Modification>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>David Kaplan</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>AMD</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Rafael Dossantos, Abraham Fernandez Rubio, Alric Althoff, Lyndon Fawcett</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Arm</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Members of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Jason Oberg</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Cycuity</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Priya B. Iyer</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Intel Corporation</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
				<Contribution Type="Content">
				  <Contribution_Name>Nicole Fern</Contribution_Name>
				  <Contribution_Organization>Riscure</Contribution_Organization>
				  <Contribution_Date>2024-01-22</Contribution_Date>
				  <Contribution_Version>4.14</Contribution_Version>
				  <Contribution_ReleaseDate>2024-02-29</Contribution_ReleaseDate>
				  <Contribution_Comment>Member of Microarchitectural Weaknesses Working Group</Contribution_Comment>
				</Contribution>
			</Content_History>
		</Weakness>
      